Contact

schawnte4554@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/schawntewilliams-taylor-71b99759 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare Healthcare Management Hospitals

Publications

Organ Donation and Transplantation. In: Critical Care Nursing, 7th Edition

Schawnte Williams-Taylor

RN, MBA/MS, CCRN, CPTC

Houston, Texas

Summary

Experienced Director Clinical Operations with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Nonprofit Organizations, Operations Management, Intensive Care, Team Building, and Media Relations. Strong healthcare and business development professional with a MSML and BSN focused on optimizing operations and establishing strong partnerships internally and externally.

Experience

LifeGift

10 years 8 months

Director Family Care February 2018 - Present (2 years 4 months)

Houston, Texas

Director of SE Organ Operations January 2018 - February 2018 (2 months)

Houston, Texas

Managing Director Clinical Operations, SE Region May 2013 - January 2018 (4 years 9 months)

Managing Director

October 2009 - May 2013 (3 years 8 months)

Manage regional operations for the West region including clinical operations and staff responsible for organ and tissue recovery, relationships with hospital and community partners.

LifeGift

9 years 10 months

Manager of Organ Recovery Services January 2005 - July 2009 (4 years 7 months)

Houston, Texas Area

In-HouseCoordinator
December 2000 - January 2005 (4 years 2 months)

Donation Clinical Specialist October 1999 - December 2000 (1 year 3 months)

Memorial Hermann Fort Bend Hospital Asst. Director ICU/ER 1994 - October 1999 (5 years) Missouri City, Texas

Initially started as a House Supervisor then transitioned to Asst. ICU Director. Managing staff and conducting daily operations of ICU/CCU. Implemented policies and procedures and collaborated with physicians on best practices.

The Methodist Hospital Registered Nurse May 1990 - 1994 (4 years) Houston, Texas

RN in Cardiovascular ICU. Provided care for patients requiring Cardiothoracic surgeries including coronary bypass, thoracic and abdominal aortic aneurysm repair, heart, lung, liver, kidney and pancreas transplantation. Served as preceptor and team lead.

Education

Western Governors University

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Business Administration,

Management and Operations · (2019 - 2019)

Western Governors University

MSML, Management and Leadership · (2016 - 2018)

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston BSN, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1988 - 1990)